<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machinelearning on Armand Sauzay</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/machinelearning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machinelearning on Armand Sauzay</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/machinelearning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Fair are Your Machine Learning Models?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/articles/how-fair-are-your-machine-learning-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/articles/how-fair-are-your-machine-learning-models/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A quick introduction to the topic of fairness with hands on coding. Evaluate your machine learning model fairness in just a few lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are Machine Learning models &amp;ldquo;fair&amp;rdquo;? When increasingly more decisions are backed by ML algorithms, it becomes important to understand the biases they can create.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But what does &amp;ldquo;fairness&amp;rdquo; mean? This is where it gets a little political (and mathematical)… To illustrate our thoughts, we&amp;rsquo;ll take the example of a machine learning model which predicts whether a salary should be higher than 50K/year based on a number of features including &lt;strong&gt;age&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;gender&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SHAP values: Machine Learning Interpretability Made Easy</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/articles/shap-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/articles/shap-values/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning interpretability is becoming increasingly important, especially as ML algorithms are getting more complex.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How good is your Machine Learning algorithm if it cant be explained? Less performant but explainable models (like linear regression) are sometimes preferred over more performant but black box models (like XGBoost or Neural Networks). This is why research around machine learning explainability (aka eXplainable AI or XAI) has recently been a growing field with amazing projects like SHAP emerging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
